STEVE ROLLINS FULL STACK WEB DEVELOPER

- coding61.sr@gmail.com
- **** 206-940-5274
- North Bend, WA
- in steven-rollins
- **O** greenhornsr

While I have spent more than 10 years as a mobility sales and ambitions reside as a web developer that excels at my craft. I have spent several months primarily learning about HTML, CSS, JavaScript, REACT, REDUX, SQLITE3, POSTGRES & more. also have exposure to ANGULAR, MONGODB, DJANGO, PYTHON, SWIFT, & more. My goal is to find a place of employment where my passion for developing quality applications improves the quality of life & experiences for end continue to grow as a contributor team that share the same passion for life, people and developer

INTERESTS INCLUDE:

Molding Digital Clay(Coding)!

Combat Sports

Basketball

Football

VOLUNTEERING:

Mt. Si View (SVSD) Head Coach Basketball Developing, leading, teaching 8-11 year old boys basic and advanced basketball skills.

i-9 Sports · Flag Football Assistant Coach Teaching 6-7 year old boys Flag Football

Soccer Assistant Coach Teaching 4-5 year olds how to play soccer.

Skills

WEB DEVELOPMENT: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, NodeJS, React, Redux, SQL-Lite, REST, GraphQL, Python, PostgreSQL, Less/Sass, Flask, Django, Angular, Jest, SQL

Projects

ghsr-portfolio

Apr. 2020 to Current

BUILT WITH: HTML | CSS | JS | REACT

Independent project designed with intent to be a simple 1 stop stop about me for any employer / recruiter.

- Folder/file structure was done with simplicity and reusability in mind.
- · Includes a ticker, a summary of me and my work, as well as links for my Github, LinkedIn, Resume and a streamlined method to email me.

URL to portfolio site: https://steven-d-rollins-portfolio.netlify.app/

Chicago Array of Things

June 2019 to June 2019

BUILT WITH: HTML | CSS | JS | REACT | REDUX | NODE.JS | EXPRESS | KNEX | POSTGRESQL | PYTHON

Chicago Array of Things was an ambitious project to allow users to visit our site to view preferred data collected by the Chicago AOT sensors.

- · Our team of 9 students from different checkpoints of WEB and Data Science curriculum were expected to build this in 4 days!
- · I was solely responsible for working with the Back End to produce a Front End that included a Client side Authorization, Login, Registration and producing a Query interface for the user that would present a graph returned from the Back End / DS team linked to the chosen query.

URL to deployed site: https://chicago-aot.netlify.app/

YELP-FEELERS

Oct. 2019 to Oct. 2019

BUILT WITH: HTML | CSS | JS | REACT | REDUX | NODE.JS | EXPRESS | KNEX | POSTGRESQL | PYTHON |

YELP FEELERS was also a cross-functional team project tasked with building an application that leveraged the YELP API to produce modified review results based on user sentiment analysis.

- · Our team consisted of 8 students from different checkpoints of WEB and Data Science curriculum and were expected to complete this in 4 days.
- · My responsibilities included Leading the project team as well as producing the BackEnd of the project.
- I made use of Node JS and Express to set up the server environment and API; used KNEX to translate JS to SQL and deploy the PostgreSQL Database; we also used the API and JWT to validate client side user data sent to the

URL to deployed site: https://practical-lamport-cc4fcf.netlify.app/

Employment

Lambda School

North Bend, WA Aug. 2019 to Nov. 2019

Team Lead(REMOTE) Full Time position. Primary responsibility was to support the learning and professional growth of Lambda Students. Often required mentoring students in the understanding of HTML, CSS, JS, REACT, HOOKS, REDUX, CONTEXT, EXPRESS, NODE.js, SQLITE3/PSQL and other associated concepts.

Bellevue, WA June 2013 to May 2015

Major Accounts Manager - Healthcare

Responsible for identifying and introducing HIPAA compliant partner solutions that solved mobility needs of western Washington's largest healthcare systems; keeping security, industry regulations, budgets and most importantly...patient safety front of mind.

Verizon Wireless

Denver, CO Nov. 2007 to June 2013

Business Account Executive New business customer procurement, management of existing customer base for businesses that had employee counts mostly ranging from 5-499.

Education

Lambda School

Apr. 2019 to Current

Coding Dojo

Oct. 2016 to Jan. 2017